好恶心
It's gross.
扔回去吧
Just throw it back.
会干的
It'll dry out.
闻起来很臭
It smells terrible.
我们可以把它倒空
We can empty it out,
装满艾丽斯小姐的鼠尾草
stuff it full of Miss Iris' sage,
还有一些薰衣草
and some of the lavender, too.
然后呢
Then what?
然后你就有一只很棒的熊
Then you have an awesome bear
曾撑过惊涛骇浪  瑞秋
that survived the stormy sea, Rachel.
我像你这么大时也有一只这样的熊
I had one just like this when I was your age, and --
该死  瞧
Oh, shit! Look!
别跑
Don't run!
一击毙命
One hit.
都没必要戳两次
I didn't have to twice.
还不错吧
Not bad, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
瞧  又一个
Look! Another one!
拜托  别跑
Come on. Don't run!
等等
Wait!
她不是浮尸
She's not a bobber.
她还活着
She's alive.
我们还是得动手
We still gotta do it.
不
No.
没必要
We don't have to do it.
有必要
Yes, we do.
没必要  只要没人发现就行
No, we don't, not if people don't find out.
我们该动手
We're supposed to.
我想动手
I want to.
我不想
I don't.
所以我们不动手
So we won't.
你会告诉别人吗
Are you gonna tell?
告诉我你会不会说出去
Just tell me if you're gonna tell,
你是不是个告密的
if you're a snitch.
我不是告密的
I'm not a snitch.
但我是不会帮忙的
But I'm not going to help.
《行尸走肉》
八个生锈的秋葵罐头
Eight rusty cans of okra
和一瓶阿司匹林
and a bottle of aspirin.
我们出来就找到这么多东西
That's what we got to show for our time out here...
除了我们还活着这一事实
...other than the fact that we're still standin'.
找东西的第一准则
Rule number one of scavenging --
这世界上尚存的所有东西都是藏起来的
there's nothing left in this world that isn't hidden.
我们只用找到它
We just have to find it.
真好
Mm, good.
我们只用找到它
We just have to find it.
有那么一阵子  我还担心呢
For a second there, I was worried.
听着  我们不该走这么远
Listen, we went farther than we were supposed to.
外面没东西了
There's nothing left out here.
就算我们想继续找
We don't even have enough gas to keep looking
也没有足够的汽油  好吗
even if we wanted to, okay?
我们说过要走两周
We said we'd be gone for two weeks.
已经两周了
It's been two weeks.
只要山顶寨遵守承诺
As long as the Hilltop keeps their side of the bargain,
家里就有食物
we have food at home.
我们需要弹药
We need ammo.
需要药物
We need medicine.
我们不能这样回去
We can't go back like this.
人们指望着我们呢
There's people counting on us.
你为什么表现得像是不知道一样
Why you acting like you don't know that?
我不确定那对我来说还有什么意义
I'm not sure that means much to me anymore.
我们在卫星站做的事
What we did at the satellite station...
我们杀掉的那些人
all of those people that we killed...
你没看见  好吗
You didn't see it, okay?
你只看见了剩下的
You just saw what was left.
不
No.
我也被迫做了
I had to do it, too.
对  我们都是被迫的
Yeah, we all had to...
为了一些牛奶和玉米
for some milk and some corn.
这不是唯一的原因
That wasn't the only reason.
我们是做了
And yeah, we did.
你知道的
You know we did.
这就是问题所在
See, that's -- that's the thing.
你看见了你们来之前
You saw how we were living back home
我们在家里是怎么过的
before you guys got there.
我们什么都不知道
We didn't know shit.
我们以为
We thought...
什么
‭What?
What?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
我现在懂了
I get it now.
如果要选择自己或者别人  就选择自己
If it's you or someone else, you choose you.
拿走所有东西  如有必要  干掉别人
You take what you can, you take out who you have to,
你就可以继续生存
and you get to keep going.
没人是一起的  好吗
Nobody's in this together, okay?
不再是了
Not anymore.
正是因为你知道自己刚刚是在胡说八道
It only hurts because you know what you just said
所以你才会难过
is total bullshit.
那不是你  希斯
That's not you, Heath.
塔拉...
Tara...
那就是我...
that's me...
也是你...
that's you...
还是所有想活着的人
and that's everybody who wants to stay alive.
那就是真相
That's the truth.
我们可以向海边走  但今天之后...
We can push towards the shore, but after today...
我们就回去
we go back.
即便我们只找到了那些生锈的罐头
Even if we just have those rusty cans.
不用  我自己来  谢了
No, I got it. Thanks.
你昨天在外面有找到什么东西吗
Did they find anything out there yesterday?
艾芙说她到开口了
Ev said she reached the mouth.
真的吗
Are you serious?
-她看见什么了  -什么都没有
- What'd she see? - ‭Nothing.
一路到那里
All the way down there.
什么都没有
Not a damn thing.
开枪啊
Go ahead.
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
我们本来就该动手
We're supposed to.
瑞秋  别
Rachel...no.
大家好
Hi.
我...我不是故意的
I just, uh... I didn't mean to.
我没有恶意
Look, I'm cool.
我不是来伤害你们的
I'm not here to hurt anyone.
瑞秋...
Rachel...
大家  把枪放下
everyone, just lower your guns.
辛蒂  离她远点
Cyndie, get away from her!
她没有干什么坏事
She hasn't done anything wrong.
这不重要
That has nothing to do with it.
退开
Get away!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是走进来了...爬进来
I just walked in -- crawled.
我都不知道自己进来了
I didn't even know I was in.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我可以离开的
I can just go.
好吧
Okay.
这样也没什么
This is cool, too.
我们就继续这样僵持着吧
We just keep doing this.
你怎么看
What do we think?
底下有很多盲点
Lotta blind spots down there.
我们先看看防水布后面有什么
Let's check behind the tarps first.
看样子他们计划着做什么
Looks like they had plans for something.
但似乎没有完成
Looks like they didn't get to finish.
挺重的
It's heavy.
里面可能有什么好东西
Could be something good in there.
塔拉
Tara.
等等  等等
Hold on. Hold on!
那边  快
That way! Go!
-希斯  -塔拉
- Heath! - ‭Tara!
希斯
Heath!
我们得听听她的说法
We just need to hear what she has to say.
不行  拖的时间越长
No. The longer we wait,
我们的社区就越危险
the more our community's at risk.
我们之前说好了  假如有人进来了的话
We agreed to discuss this together as a group
我们要小组表决
if someone ever got in.
我们很早以前就决定了的
We made that decision a long time ago.
在我们开始前  你需要用下洗手间吗
Do you, uh, need to use the bathroom before we get started?
不用了  谢谢
No. Um, thank you.
但也许...
But maybe...
我是娜塔尼亚
I'm Natania.
这是凯西和碧翠丝
This is Kathy and Beatrice,
你已经见过了
whom you've already met.
只有我一个人听到铃声了吗
Am I the only one hearing bells?
那是我们设的铃
They're ours.
我们设了六个
We have six of them --
有些在附近  有些在几里之外
some nearby, some a couple of miles away.
那些汽笛声又是怎么回事
What about the air horn?
我们只能找到有限的铃铛
We could only find so many bells.
它们是用来引走那些
They are to redirect any of the dead
被吸引来的行尸的
that might have been drawn by it.
不赖嘛
Not bad.
有时是挺有用的
It helps sometimes.
但风中的树枝  树叶的沙沙作响...
But a branch in the wind, leaves rustling...
我们很幸运这一带还挺干净的
We're lucky this is a relatively clear area.
当时那些撤离  那些驳船...
The evacuations, the barges --
也不知道真假
if they were even real.
所以...
So...
你是从哪里来的
where are you from?
亚特兰大...
Atlanta...
那是很久之前的事了
a long time ago.
我不断移动
I just stayed on the move.
我朋友和我...
My friend and I --
我们已经自力更生
we've been traveling around
在外面闯荡好几年了
on our own for a couple years now.
我们之前在一艘渔船上工作
We used to work on a fishing boat.
有人跟你一起吗
There's someone with you?
本来是的
There was.
我们分开了
We got separated.
你在什么样的渔船上工作
What kind of fishing boat did you work on --
拖网渔船  围网渔船还是库船
trawler, seiner, larder?
是你说的最后一个
Oh, last one. You got it.
你来这干什么
What were you doing here?
你必须理解  当有人发现来这的方法时
You must understand, we get nervous when people just find their way
我们会很紧张
into our home.
是啊  见识过了
Yeah, I-I saw that.
我和我的朋友
My friend and I --
我们发现了一个建在桥上的居住地
we found this settlement built on a bridge,
或者说是被遗弃的居住地
or what was left of it.
我们当时在搜刮资源
We were scavenging,
然后被行尸攻击了  就是死人
and we got attacked by walkers -- the dead.
我们设法逃离
We were trying to get away from them,
然后我被撞到了桥下
and I got knocked off a bridge.
我在水流里挣扎
I fought the current,
最后被冲到了水湾
wound up in the inlet.
是河口吗
The estuary?
还是海湾
The bay?
我地理不好
Look, I'm not good with geography.
我只是以为我死在那了
I just thought I was dead out there.
然后我到了海岸  就昏过去了
And I got to the shore, and I just passed out.
那是温莎河上的桥
It's the bridge on Windsor.
你...你知道怎么去那吗
You -- you know how to get there?
我们知道
We do.
她没有回答问题
She didn't answer the question.
我没有吗
I didn't?
问题是什么
What was the question?
你来这干什么
What were you doing here?
当那个女孩辛蒂给我拿了食物
When that girl, Cyndie, brought me food,
我就假装昏迷  然后跟着她来的
I just pretended like I was out and I followed her back.
看起来她有一个营地
It seemed like she had a camp,
我想看看我是否能得到帮助
and I wanted to see if I could get any help.
那你为什么偷偷摸摸的
Then why were you sneaking around?
我想看看是否安全
I wanted to see if it was safe.
依然不确定
Still not sure.
我很抱歉把你们吓到了
Look, I'm sorry that I freaked you out.
真心的
Really.
但如果你们告诉我怎么走  我就离开
But if you just point me in the right direction, I'm gone.
我得回到桥那找我的朋友
I need to get back to the bridge and look for my friend.
如果我们放你走
If we let you go,
你会对我们很不利
you have us at a disadvantage.
你已经了解我们不少了
You know a great deal about us now.
-如果你们放我走吗  -没错
- If you let me go? - Yes.
正常来说  我们已经把你杀了
You see, normally, we would've killed you already.
陌生人进入营地  我们是格杀勿论的
We shoot strangers on sight if they come into our camp.
但碧翠丝说你没杀她
But Beatrice said you spared her life,
而且我的孙女舍命救你
and my granddaughter almost lost hers trying to save you --
就是"那个女孩"辛蒂
"That girl," Cyndie.
所以我们还剩一个问题
So it leaves us with the question still
就是应该怎么处置你
of what to do with you instead.
是啊
Yeah.
确实难以抉择
That's a pickle, all right.
你不妨休息一下
Why don't you rest up?
我们之后再谈
We'll talk more later.
也许我们有人可以想出好主意
Maybe one of us will have a brainstorm.
好的
Cool.
希望你喜欢吃鱼
Hope you like fish.
干的那种
the dried kind?
她给你的是咸鲈鱼
She brought you salted perch.
你喜欢吗
Did you like it?
当然
Sure.
你不喜欢
No, you didn't.
没那么喜欢
Not so much.
我们有炖菜
We're having stew.
对了
Oh, that's right --
你们两还没有正式见过面对吧
you two haven't formally met, have you?
塔拉  这是辛蒂
Tara, this is Cyndie.
多谢你在海滩上帮我
Uh, thank you for the beach and...
还有之前发生的一切
everything out there.
你救了我的命
I mean, you saved my life.
真的
You did.
我不知道你奶奶是否完全同意  但...
I mean, I don't know if your grandma totally approves, but...
我妈妈会同意的
My mom would've.
她给我指引过方向
She showed me the way.
一种方向
A way.
我本来想指给瑞秋看的
I was trying to show Rachel.
那个小女孩
The little girl?
是的
Yeah.
她还没有动过手
She hasn't had to do it yet.
你呢
Have you?
我射得很准
I'm a really good shot.
没错
Yes, you are.
我们吃东西吧
Okay, let's eat.
好好聊聊
Let's talk.
塔拉
Tara.
你上一次吃东西是什么时候
When was the last time you ate?
酱油包算食物吗
Do soy-sauce packets count as food?
我们这里无限供应鱼肉
We have an endless supply of fish here --
这就是住在海边的好处之一
one of the perks of living so close to the ocean.
塔拉  你觉得
You, um, you think, Tara,
你能适应吗
it's something you could get used to?
我希望能劝你留下来
I'm hoping to convince you to stay.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
为什么不呢
Why not?
这样就能完美地解决我们的问题
It would be the perfect solution to our problem.
我们的村庄依然隐秘
We keep our village a secret,
你也能安定下来
and you'd get to put down roots.
你是一名厉害的战士  塔拉  也是好人
You're a skilled fighter, Tara, and a good person.
我能看得出来
I can tell that.
你不会抛下任何东西
You wouldn't be leaving anything behind.
如果你想要的话  我们能帮你找到你的朋友
And if you want, we can help you find your friend.
如果他愿意留下来  我们也能给他一个家
And if he wants to stay, we'll offer him a home, too.
他也能留在这里
He could stay here?
为什么不行呢
Is there a reason why not?
我是说...
I mean...
我从来没想到我会问这个问题
well, I never thought I'd be asking this,
但是这里的男人哪去了
but where are all the men?
全都死了
All of them?
我们和另一群人起了点冲突
We got into a skirmish with another group.
他们全都死了
None of them made it.
我们也损失了不少女人
And we lost others, too.
辛蒂本来还有个11岁的弟弟  我的小孙子
Cyndie had an 11-year-old brother, my grandson,
还有他们的母亲  我的女儿也死了
and their mother, too, my daughter.
后来  我们决定不管怎么样
After that, we decided to protect ourselves,
都要保护好自己
no matter what.
不管我们碰见谁  都格杀勿论
No matter who we crossed, we would kill on sight.
我们收拾了几件衣服  就离开了原来的家
We left our old home with just the clothes on our backs.
然后我们找到了这里
And then we found this place.
我们会一直躲在这里
We would stay hidden.
我们也会一直活着
And we would stay alive.
塔拉  你本来可以伤害我们  但你没有
Tara, you could have hurt us, and you didn't.
我知道你肯定觉得我们是一群禽兽
I-I know we must sound like monsters to you,
但我必须把实话告诉你
but I had to be honest
这样或许你能理解我们为什么这样做
so maybe you could understand why we do it.
或许你能...
Maybe you could...
考虑留下来
consider staying.
或许你也能实话告诉我们
And maybe you could be honest with us
你从哪里来
about where you're from.
我说的是实话
I was telling you the truth.
真的吗
Really?
你说你在渔船上工作过  库船
You said you worked on a fishing boat, a larder.
没错
That's right.
塔拉  库船是储藏肉类的仓库
Tara, a larder is a room used for storing meat.
好吧  我是在撒谎
Yeah. I was lying.
我来自一个社区
I come from a community.
的确就是一个社区
And that's really what it is.
我们住在一起  相互扶持
We live with each other. We help each other.
有墙  房子
We have walls, houses.
我有一个让我挂念的女朋友
I have a girlfriend I want to get back to.
我们做过...
And we've done things...
和你们一样的事
just like you.
有一些人
There were these people.
他们威胁我们
They were threatening us.
我们发现他们的行动基地是一个老卫星站
We found out they were using an old satellite station to operate out of.
我们趁半夜去到那里  然后我们
We went out there in the middle of the night, and we...
干掉了他们  每一个人
took them out, every one of them.
这些人都是罪有应得
These people got what they deserved.
他们选择杀戮和威胁别人
They chose to kill and to terrorize people,
但我们不是因此而杀他们的
but that's not why we killed them.
我们不是为了让这个世界变得更好
We didn't do it to make the world a better place.
我们是为了活命  和你们一样
We did it because we wanted to stay alive, just like you.
我知道你们认为让我留下来
And I know that you think that me staying
是唯一的办法
is the only solution.
但我有个好主意
Well, how's this for brainstorming --
也许我们两个团体能合作
maybe our groups can start working together.
我们刚告诉你
We just told you
我们不希望任何人知道这个地方
that we don't want anyone to know about this place.
你们不能永远这么活下去
You can't live like that forever.
我觉得我们可以
I think we can.
我...我明白你们这样做的原因
Look, I -- I get why you're doing it,
但如果你们一直把所有人都当做敌人
but if you keep seeing everyone as an enemy,
那你们就只有敌人
then enemies are all you're gonna find.
你们迟早会需要朋友的
Sooner or later, you're gonna need a friend.
我们可以相互保护
We can protect each other.
我们会比之前更安全...
We'd be safer than we are --
好吧
All right.
我们能派人给她带路
We could send a guide out with her.
帮她找她的朋友
Help her look for her friend,
然后一起去他们的社区
and then continue on to their community,
只是去看看那里是什么样
just -- just to see what it's like.
好  我去
Yeah, I'll do it.
我想跟她一块去
I want to go with her.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
你之前没有留路线方案
You left without leaving a routing plan,
没有跟守卫通告就擅自离开
without signing with the gate.
辛蒂  我以为我们谈过这些问题了
Cyndie, I thought we were through with all this.
没错
We are.
在你学会什么叫责任之前
You will be staying behind the fence
都要在围栏里待着
until you learn some responsibility.
要是这事成了
If this works out,
会有很多别的机会
there will be plenty of other chances.
要是不成
And if it doesn't...
我不想你待在外面
I don't want you there.
会有别的机会的
There will be other chances.
你确定没有叫库船的渔船吗
Are you sure there isn't a fishing boat called a larder?
我还蛮确定有...
'Cause I'm, like, pretty sure that --
-没有  -那好吧
- There isn't. - ‭Yeah. Fair enough.
一切会有好转的
This is gonna get better --
大家团结起来
people getting together.
世界就能像之前一样
That's how the world is gonna be the world again.
我希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
注意安全
Be safe.
辛蒂呢
Where's Cyndie?
她在房间里生闷气呢
She's in the cabin, sulking.
要是她遵守了规矩
We wouldn't be doing this
我们就不会做这些了
if it wasn't for her breaking all the rules.
祝你好运  塔拉
Good luck, Tara.
好吧
Yeah.
我们之后再多练习下  娜塔尼亚
you know, we'll -- we'll work on that, Natania.
谢谢你
Thank you.
再见
See you soon.
回见了  瑞秋
See you later, Rachel.
碧翠丝
Hey, Beatrice.
抱歉打了你
I'm sorry about the hit.
算你走运
Well, you got lucky.
的确
Yeah, I did.
我们离桥还有多远
How far are we to the bridge?
还有一半路程
About halfway there.
跟紧点
Stick close.
这里林子很密
It's pretty thick through here.
我来吧
I got it.
拜托
Please.
在村里时我本可以杀了你
I could have killed you back in the village.
放我走
Let me go.
你什么都没有
You don't have anything left.
你的人都死了
Your people are dead.
救世军
The Saviors.
你们捣毁的那个卫星站
That satellite post you took out --
你们完全不知道自己惹上了什么
you have no idea what you started.
我们什么都没惹上
We didn't start anything.
我们终结了一切  他们都死了
We ended it. They're dead.
你没有阻止他们
You didn't stop them.
你也阻止不了他们
You can't stop them.
那只是个哨站
That was just an outpost.
还有更多  更多的救世军
There are more -- more Saviors...
更多的哨站
more outposts.
他们要是知道你的朋友们
If they know about your friends...
那他们就已经没救了
it's already too late for them.
救世军
The Saviors...
是他们干的吗
they did this to you?
是他们把你们所有男性都杀了吗
They're the ones that killed all your men?
所有男性
Every man...
所有超过十岁的男孩
every boy over 10.
他们让他们排好队  用枪射他们的头
They lined 'em up, shot 'em in the head.
我们反抗过
You see, we tried to fight...
就像你们一样
just like you.
他们赢了
They won.
我们本该一直替他们工作
And we were supposed to keep working for them.
然后某一晚  我们逃跑了
Then one night, we just left.
我们脱身了  懂吗
We got away, okay?
我们不会让你把他们引回来
We are not gonna let you lead them back to us.
他们会得到他们想要的
They get what they want.
对不起  你没有...
I'm sorry you didn't get --
走  快跑
Go! Run!
等等
Wait!
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna shoot me.
因为我救了你吗
Because I saved you?
救了三次了
Three times now.
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna shoot me.
你必须发誓
You have to swear...
你永远不会回来
that you'll never come back
你永远不会说出我们这里
and you'll never tell anyone about us,
对你们自己人也不能说
not even your own people.
我为什么要回来
Why...would I come back?
我为什么要对别人说这里
Why would I tell anyone about this place?
因为也许你能得到一些好处
Because maybe you could get something out of it --
任何好处
anything.
我们为什么杀掉那两个靠近我们的人
Why did we kill those two people who just came near us?
你们为什么杀掉卫星站里的所有人
Why did you kill all those people at that satellite station?
因为你们都以为必须做
Because you all thought you had to.
但你们不必
But none of you had to.
你们只是做了
You just did.
没人是坏人
Nobody's evil.
他们只是选择了忘记自己是谁
They just decide to forget who they are.
你必须发誓
You have to swear.
有些人真是坏人  辛蒂
Some people are evil, Cyndie.
我见过
I've seen it.
所以我必须现在就回去
That's why I have to get back now.
你必须发誓
You have to swear.
我发誓
I swear.
给
Here.
食物和水
Food and water.
走吧
‭C'mon.
我带你去桥上
I'll take you to the bridge.
这次别掉下去了
Try not to fall off this time.
-不只这些  对吗  -对  还有很多
- There's more, right? - Yeah, a lot.
我会用车作掩护  直到被发现
I'll use the cars as cover until I can't anymore.
然后呢
Then what?
我会跑
I'll run.
我喜欢跑
I love to run.
这是我最喜欢的事
It's my favorite thing.
你跑不过去的
You'll never make it.
我可以的
Yeah, I will.
让我帮你
Let me help you.
你已经帮过了  你送我来了这里
You already did. You got me here.
回去吧  告诉她们我袭击了你
Just go back. Tell them that I attacked you.
她们了解你  塔拉
They know you, Tara.
不  告诉她们你杀了我
No, tell them you killed me.
她们也了解我
They know me.
你知道我不会去任何地方的
You know I'm not going anywhere
除非你安全抵达另一边
until you get to the other side -- safe.
我有枪  我有子弹
I've got my rifle. I've got ammo.
我送你来这里不是看你死的
I didn't get you here just to watch you die.
所以我们快点完事吧  好吗
So let's just get this over with, okay?
凯西和碧翠丝  她们知道我们要来这里
Kathy and Beatrice -- they know we were coming here.
她们要来了
They're coming.
好
Okay.
你为什么跟她们其他人不同
Why aren't you like the rest of them,
经历了这么多事以后
after everything that's happened?
你为什么不同
Why aren't you?
好吧
Okay.
好  上那边
Okay, up on that side.
快
Go!
希斯
Heath!
希斯  我来了
Heath, I'm coming!
我来了
I'm coming!
不  快跑  快跑
No! Go! Go!
我们是一起的
We're in this together!
我知道
I know.
也许是你
Maybe that was you.
我希望是你
I hope that was you.
(太阳镜  古玩)
(欢迎来到亚历山大安全区   迷途者的天堂  掠夺者的地狱)
我很遗憾  塔拉
I'm sorry, Tara.
我也很遗憾
I'm sorry, too.
我们不用只坐在这里
We don't have to just sit here.
枪  弹药
Guns, ammunition...
你有什么线索吗
you don't have any leads?
任何东西  任何地方
Anything, anywhere.
我不管那里看起来有多么危险
I don't care how dangerous it looked.
告诉我个地方
Tell me a place.
我会去的
I'll go.
一定有什么地方
There's gotta be somewhere.
我们可以解决这事
We can square this.
我们可以纠正这事
We can make this right.
我们必须这样做
We have to.
我们做不到
We can't.
我在外面没找到任何东西
I didn't see anything like that out there.